<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/Vault/P5/current/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>

<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/Vault/P5/current/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">

  <teiHeader>

      <fileDesc>

         <titleStmt>

            <title>Blacks Left Out of Medical Picture</title>
              <author>
                <persName>
                  <forename> Charles
                  <forename> Jeffery
                  <surname> Sneiderman
                  <surname> Blum
                  </surname>
                </surname>
              </forename>
            </forename>
                </persName>
              </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp> This is an attempt to textually encode a document about Black medical doctors during the Civil Rights era
               </resp>
              <persName> D'Arcee Neal </persName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Published in Diamondback Student Newspaper September 19th, 1968 </p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Accessed from the University of Maryland online digital archive</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div>
          <p> <seg type="headline"> "Blacks Left Out of Medical Picture" </seg> </p>

            <p>The serious shortage of physicians and dentists this nation <seg type="error"> <supplied>lacks</supplied> </seg> is a fact ac­
            knowledged by federal experts and public alike. However, one of the least known
            aspects of this problem is the appalling shortage of Black physicians and dentists.
            Among white <seg type="important"> <choice> <orig> = A m e r i c a n s </orig> <reg>Americans</reg> </choice> </seg>, one out of every 670 is a physician but among Black
          </p>
          <cb/>
          <p>
            Americans, only one in <seg type="number"> 5,000 </seg> practices medicine. Whereas there is one dentist for
            every 1,750 Americans there is only one Black dentist for every <seg type="number"> 10,000 </seg> Black Americans.
            The crux of the problem is that there
          </p>
          <cb/>
          <p>
            are far too few Black college students who enter medical and dental schools. There appear
            to be four principal <sic>rea­ sons</sic> that these schools are not attract­ing a sufficient number of qualified Negro
            applicants. </p>
            <p>The <seg type="number"> first </seg> reason is that among Negro college students, many lack the life-long <seg type="important"><choice> <orig> = a c a d e m i c </orig> <reg>
            academic </reg> </choice> </seg> preparation necessary to pursue the highly demanding and com­petitive pre-dental and pre-medical cur­
            ricula. </p>
            <p> <seg type="number"> Secondly, </seg> a lack of communication exists between medical and dental schools and Black
            undergraduates, resulting in a belief among the latter that racial origin is a serious deterrent to a
            career in medicine or dentistry. </p>
            <p> The <seg type="number"> third </seg> reason is that many Black students feel the cost of dental or med­ical education would be prohibitive. </p>
            <p> The <seg type="number"> fourth </seg> is that many Black students are unaware of the opportunities which
            would be opened to them as physicians and dentists. </p>
            <p> We feel that these four reasons should
            not deter any Black student on this cam­pus from the attainment of worthwhile careers in dentistry or medicine. </p>
            <p> For the Black student who finds his background inadequate in any subject, he can readily obtain tutoring assistance by </p>
            <cb/>
            <p> <quote> The various clinical colleges and academies, like the American College
            of Surgeons and the American Col­lege of Physicians have practically eliminated their racial bars so that Negro physicians are admitted
            Just as others, as soon as properly qualified and sponsored. </quote> </p>
            <p> Similarly, the <seg type="important"> <choice> <orig> v a r i o u s </orig> <reg> various </reg> </choice> </seg> specialty boards certify Negro physicians as
            specialists without <sic> restrict!cm </sic> when they have met the respective training requirements and passed the examin­ations.
          </p>
          <cb/>
          <p>
            For the Black student who needs finan­cial assistance, there are numerous <seg type="important"> <choice> <orig> a w a r d s </orig> <reg> awards </reg> </choice> </seg> available from professional schools, medical societies, Federal and
            state governments, and various other sources. </p>
          <p> <seg type="important"> <choice> <orig> A g a i n </orig> <reg> Again </reg> </choice> </seg> quoting from Ebony, "Today there are more medical school openings available to Negro students than
            there can be found qualified applicants to fill. <emph> *For example, Harvard Medical School plans to provide at least <seg type="number"> 15 </seg> scholarships per class for disadvantaged
            students. </emph> For the Black student, a career in den­tistry or medicine offers the opportunity for a constructive role in attaining social, economic, and political
            equality in any community. President Johnson proclaimed to mem­bers of the National Medical Associa­tion in a recent address that Negro professional men
            must be their <emph> "broth­ers' keepers* </emph> and <quote>"...must provide the leadership, the brains and courage." </quote> The Pre-Dental and Pre-Medical so­cieties strongly urge any
            Black students interested in these professions to in­vestigate our programs.
            <persName> Charles Sneiderman </persName>
            <persName> Jeffery Blum </persName>
            <roleName> Pre-Medical societies and Pre-Dental </roleName>
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
